# **Aman Sharma**

amansh2786@gmail.com

7772022415 aman-sharma-3524a91a6/ github.com/amanshr72 Noida, Gwalior

#### Summary

Solution-focused Web Developer with experience in web-based applications. Involved in the creation and execution of web-based solutions, supporting corporate goals and plans while developing practical knowledge of various platforms and effective development methods.

shown expertise with Front-End PHP, WordPress, and JavaScript to create websites with a strong focus on the user. good understanding of user experience, speed, and web design best practices.

Code chef --> 3\*

Hacker Rank --> CPP 5%, Problem-solving 3%

Education

# **Amity University**

BCA -2023

#### IANT

CHNA-SC -2020

## Greenwood Public School

XII and X -2018

## Skills

- React.js
- Node.js
- MongoDB
- OOP'
- JAVA
- C++
- HTML5
- Bootstrap
- WordPress
- JSON

- jQuery
- MySQL
- Express.js
- JavaScript
- C
- Tailwind CSS
- CSS3
- Git
- GitHub
- AJAX

## Experience

## Web Developer

Suvidha Foundation 08/2021 - 10/2021

- Co-ordinated with project officers with seniority.
- Leads the Front-End Team and uses React-JS to build web pages.
- Backend work included creating a login page and utilizing phpMyAdmin to store user credentials in MySQL.
- Additionally, let people log in using their Facebook and Google accounts.
- while preserving responsiveness and developing code.
- https://www.suvidhafoundationedutech.org/

Web Developer 09/2021 - 11/2021

#### CariKture

- Developed several websites.
- work with seniors on the website that the customer has given to the organization.
- worked together on several development projects.
- Additionally, I wrote & maintained webpage content.
- For whiteboard animation, created some svg (animated CSS text). & So on.
- devised ways to fulfil deadlines and maintained clear, precise project plans.

Web Developer 06/2022 - 07/2022

Algozini Services Pvt. Ltd.

- Redesigned the website to create a more visually appealing, user-friendly experience
- Meeting with clients to discuss website design and function.
- Designing and building the website front-end.
- Designing and managing the website back-end including database and server integration.
- Conducting website performance tests.
- Troubleshooting content issues.
- Conducting WordPress training with the client.
- Monitoring the performance of the live website.
- http://algozini.in/, https://evsmart.co.in

#### Certificates

- · Getting Started with Node Js
- · React Js
- EHE
- CompTIA IT Fundamentals+

- JavaScript & jQuery with Vue JS intro
- Cloud Computing
- · Red Hat Certified System Administrator
- CompTIA Network+

#### Project

- 1. GUSTO (restaurant website)
  - static restaurant website uses html, css, java, bootstrap, and tailwind css
  - Technology used: html, css, java, bootstrap, and tailwind css.
  - Link: https://amanshr72.github.io/gusto/
- 2. CollegeSpace (WordPress blog page) (under construction)
  - Blog webpage with notes, question papers, assignment aid, and so on..
  - section-"learn by language" with various resources, videos, and notes to learn programming languages.
  - Link: <a href="http://collegespace.42web.io">http://collegespace.42web.io</a>
- 3. resume-builder (online resume builder tool)
  - Quick and Easy Online Resume Builder
  - Technology used react js, JavaScript, jQuery, jsx, bootstrap, material ui,
  - Link: https://amanshr72.github.io/resume-builder/
- 4. Chocolate & More (restaurant booking website)
  - Dynamic restaurant reservation website. This is a web-based application that provides the Restaurant's Customers with Possible Customers with an online platform to reserve a table on their desired date and time.
  - Technology used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, PHP, and MySQL.
  - Link: <a href="http://aman-sharma-restaurant-reservation.rf.gd/?i=1">http://aman-sharma-restaurant-reservation.rf.gd/?i=1</a>